

# Inderpal Singh

Full Stack Developer

Web Application Developer with 8 years of experience in the development and consultancy of web applications in PHP, Angular, React and Node Js. Writes excellent state of the art, robust and reliable code with style. Advance level of programming skills from architecture to API designs. Successfully delivered medium to large-scale applications with millions of users, on time and on value

ips13009@gmail.com

(+91) 8591773009

imsingh.com

github.com/ips13

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Technical Lead Manager illuminz

06/2018 - 06/2021

My responsibility was to lead the team of technical developers and help them to solve the problems. I was communicating with clients, listen to their thoughts and discuss all the project-related stuff. I gave weekly demos and discuss the next milestones with them to deliver the quality and on-time work.

#### Roles

- Technical Lead
- Client Handling

## Senior Software Engineer Deftsoft

01/2017 - 05/2018

Mohali, India

I worked on different technologies and communicate with sales and team leads to give a right direction, timeline, and availabilities for the projects. Successfully built and maintained a variety of customer-facing applications. Worked closely with the project team during User Acceptance Testing and Implementation phases to ensure a successful and timely outcome.

# Senior Web Developer Webclouds

10/2013 - 10/2016

Mohali, India

I started my development journey from Webclouds as a trainee in PHP development, within 20days I covered the syllabus given to me and I was assigned to live projects, I made the first project in WordPress and completed that within 4 days.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Bsc.IT

## Kalinga University, Raipur

06/2014 - 06/2016

Raipur, India

- Trainings - PHP
- HTML/CSS

# Diploma in IT (DIT) Punjab infotech

10/2012 - 10/2013

Mohali, India

Mohali, India

COLLEGE

Web Development

## **Higher Secondary JVS**

03/2011 - 03/2012

Courses

- Non-Medical
- Math

## SKILLS



## PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Motoview

- https://motoview.com
- A complete website with a listing of cars from different motor shows, the best automobile companies from around the world showcase their latest designs and concepts for cars of the future. We are fetching a list of different cars from the Iceberg API and then storing all of them inside Motoview database. We can compare the multiple cars side by side to see all the features available, also users can signup and like/unlike, comment on the different parts of
- Angular, Laravel, Mysql, AWS

## Ehtnico

- https://ethnico.in
- Ethnico presents itself as a holistic platform for both customized and readymade clothing. It connects artisans, boutiques, and clothing houses across Chennai, to people looking for bespoke stitching and customized tailoring experiences. Ethnico is a wholesome platform for both the end-users and the vendors. It gives users the feasibility to shop for readymade garments and bespoke stitching options, without having to step out of their homes.
- React, NodeJS, Mysql, Mongo, AWS

#### Lex Chathot

- The chatbot is made to take the feedback for the different Canadian surveys, based on user response it detects the sentiment of the line, if it's positive or negative response based on that it asks the next question to get the more details about their experience, it has progress bar until it reaches the certain number of words the questions continue asking for 5 times to the user. I made a unique Lambda/Python script to achieve this and prepare the sentence by using English grammar and syntax.
- React, AWS Lambda, Python, DynamoDB

## LANGUAGES

English

Punjabi

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

## INTERESTS

Cricket

Music

Writina

Coding